Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 1: Manuscripts, 1916-1987; 15.25 Linear Feet in 34 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box.
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 73, Folder 176, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 73, Folder 177, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 73, Folder 178, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 73, Folder 179, Item 1)
  - Gam -- working manuscript, circa 1924 (Box 74, Folder 180, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- notes, circa 1961 (Box 74, Folder 181, Item 1)
  - Station am Horizont / Station at the Horizon -- notes, letter, circa 1927-1928 (Box 74, Folder 181, Item 2)
  - Journalisten -- notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 181, Item 3)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- newspaper clippings, 1959 (Box 74, Folder 181, Item 4)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 74, Folder 182, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 74, Folder 183, Item 1-2)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- notes, circa 1961 (Box 74, Folder 183, Item 3)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die -- working manuscript working manuscript, circa 1954 (Box 74, Folder 183, Item 4)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript (translation), circa 1961 (Box 74, Folder 184, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript (translation), circa 1961 (Box 75, Folder 185, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 75, Folder 186, Item 1-3)
  - Gam -- working manuscript, circa 1924 (Box 75, Folder 187, Item 1-3)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- galley proof with inscription (translation), 1963 (Box 75, Folder 188, Item 1)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- working manuscript, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 189, Item 1)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- working manuscript, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 190, Item 1)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- TV script working manuscript, circa 1961-1962 (Box 75, Folder 191, Item 1)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- galley proof, 1963 (Box 76, Folder 192, Item 1)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- working manuscript, circa 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 193, Item 1)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk -- notes, circa 1956 (Box 76, Folder 194, Item 1-4)
  - Arc de Triomphe / Arch of Triumph -- notes, circa 1945 (Box 76, Folder 194, Item 5)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- notes, circa 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 194, Item 6)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk -- notes, circa 1956 (Box 76, Folder 194, Item 7)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- notes, circa 1961 (Box 76, Folder 194, Item 8)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- working manuscript, circa 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 195, Item 1-3)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- notes, circa 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 196, Item 1-3)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die -- working manuscript working manuscript, circa 1954 (Box 76, Folder 196, Item 4)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- working manuscript, circa 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 197, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 198, Item 1-3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 199, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 200, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 201, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 202, Item 1-2)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 203, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 204, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 205, Item 1-2)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 77, Folder 205, Item 3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 206, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 207, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 208, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 209, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 210, Item 1-2)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 210, Item 3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 210, Item 4)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 1)
  - Brunnenstraße -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 2)
  - "Full Circle / Die letzte Station" -- short story notes, circa 1956 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 3)
  - "Berlin Stories" -- notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 4)
  - New York Intermezzo -- notes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 5-7)
  - New York Intermezzo, "Stories of Porto Ronco", Irrenanstalt -- notes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 8)
  - New York Intermezzo -- notes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 9-10)
  - Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon -- notes, circa 1961-1962 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 11)
  - Trotzki -- notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 12)
  - Brunnenstraße -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 13)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 211, Item 14)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 212, Item 1-3)
  - Der Kranke -- outline, undated (Box 78, Folder 213, Item 1)
  - Full Circle / Die letzte Station -- notes, circa 1956 (Box 78, Folder 213, Item 2)
  - Der Kranke -- working manuscript, undated (Box 78, Folder 213, Item 3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- dramatization notes, circa 1931 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 2)
  - New York Intermezzo -- notes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 4)
  - New York Intermezzo -- notes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 5-6)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 214, Item 7-8)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 215, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 215, Item 2-3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 215, Item 4)
  - "Ihr kleinen Hotels von New York" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 78, Folder 215, Item 5)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 78, Folder 215, Item 6)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 216, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 217, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 218, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 219, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 220, Item 1-3)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- notes, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 221, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 221, Item 2)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 222, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 223, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 224, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- working manuscript, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 79, Folder 225, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- printer's copy, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 226, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- printer's copy, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 227, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- clean copy, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 228, Item 1)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- clean copy, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 229, Item 1)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- draft, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 1)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 2-5)
  - Station am Horizont / Station at the Horizon -- notes, letter, 1921 (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 6)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 7)
  - "Ein Fischer ist der Dichter" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 8)
  - "Der Tod ist tot" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 9)
  - "Welt - Eros" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 10)
  - "Gark" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 11)
  - "Und wenn Du aus dem Taumel um Brunst und Brot" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 230, Item 12-13)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- clean copy, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 231, Item 1)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- working manuscript, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 232, Item 1)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- clean copy, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 232, Item 2)
  - Gam -- notes, circa 1924 (Box 81, Folder 233, Item 1)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- notes, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 233, Item 2-3)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 233, Item 4)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- notes, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 233, Item 5-7)
  - Die Heimkehr des Enoch J. Jones / The Return of Enoch J. Jones -- clean copy, circa 1952-1955 (Box 81, Folder 233, Item 8)
  - Heinz und Ruth -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 234, Item 1)
  - Kleines Schicksal -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 235, Item 1-2)
  - Kleines Schicksal -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 235, Item 3)
  - Kleines Schicksal -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 235, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 81, Folder 235, Item 5-6)
  - "Stories of Porto Ronco" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 236, Item 1)
  - "Stories of Porto Ronco" -- newspaper clippings, 1953 (Box 81, Folder 236, Item 2)
  - "Der letzte Romantiker" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 1-2)
  - Last Requiem -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 3)
  - "Der letzte Romantiker" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 4)
  - Das Buch Ruth -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 5)
  - "Der letzte Romantiker" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 6)
  - "Freimädel" -- working manuscript, 1922 (Box 81, Folder 237, Item 7)
  - "The Liberation of X.Y.Z." -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 238, Item 1)
  - "The Liberation of X.Y.Z." -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 238, Item 2)
  - "Fragt Freund" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 1)
  - Stimmen -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 2)
  - Stimmen -- newspaper clipping, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 4)
  - "Dichter erlebt Feuilleton" -- notes, 1921 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 5)
  - Jugendbuch -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 6)
  - "Die Novellen vom Tode" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 7)
  - "Die Vision des Präsidenten" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 8)
  - "Fritz" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 9)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- notes, circa 1929 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 10)
  - "Pointe des Lebens" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 11)
  - "Eisenbahnattentat" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 12)
  - Berlin 45 -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 13)
  - "Ravic" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 14)
  - "Die Novellen vom Tode" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 15)
  - "Stories of Porto Ronco" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 16)
  - Paulette -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 17)
  - "Kitsch" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 18)
  - "Five o'clock" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 19)
  - "Kleiner Gehilfe" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 20)
  - Gam -- notes, circa 1924 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 21)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- working manuscript, circa 1961 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 22)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- notes, circa 1961 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 23)
  - La Barcarole -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 24)
  - "Book, Schizo" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 25)
  - Operation Sunrise -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 26)
  - "Trollmann" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 27)
  - Full Circle / Die letzte Station -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 81, Folder 239, Item 28)
  - "Die Sonette (oder Gedichte) von der ewigen Liebe und dem Betrug" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 240, Item 1)
  - "Und wenn Du aus dem Taumel um Brunst und Brot" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 1)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 2)
  - "Geschichte eines Bauern" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 3)
  - "Schlanker Page" -- working manuscipt, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 4)
  - Thematic collection, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 5)
  - "Henriette Torstensen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 6)
  - "Henriette Torstensen" -- newspaper clipping, undated (Box 81, Folder 241, Item 7)
  - "Ach der Herbst hat sich erhoben" and "Und der Schnaps hat sich erhoben" -- working manuscripts, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 1)
  - Song ("Ich habe nichts als ein paar Erinnerungen") -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 2)
  - "Noch Schmerz! Die Wunden offen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 3)
  - "Verklärte Nacht" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 4)
  - "Lied der Emigranten" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 5)
  - "Du, Allerseelen allzufrüh gefallener Schnee" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 6)
  - "Aufbruch" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 7)
  - Pat -- notes, circa 1932 (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 8)
  - "Hebt sich Dein schimmerndes Gesicht" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 9)
  - "In der sanften Verlassenheit des Glücks" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 10)
  - "Die Blätter fallen und der Regen fällt" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 11)
  - "Sometimes the sudden fright" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 12)
  - "Grey cars rattling" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 13)
  - "Man braucht ein starkes" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 14)
  - "Zärtliche Leidenschaft" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 15)
  - "Wenn aber das Blut dunkler" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 16)
  - "Und die Birken häufen schon anderes über seine Ufer" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 17)
  - "Rote Segel über dem weindunklen Abendmeer" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 18)
  - Song ("Du sagst, ich betrüge Dich mit einem andern") -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 19)
  - "Eine kleine Hoffnung ging auf Reisen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 20)
  - "Wir wollen den Abend stürmen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 21)
  - "Süßer und bitterer Wind" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 22)
  - "Lied vom Regen" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 23)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 24)
  - "Liebe" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 25)
  - "Wie kann denn das sein" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 26)
  - "Die Wärme der Erde an den Füßen noch fühlend" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 27)
  - "Ravic aber stand nahe" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 28)
  - "Ufer nur sind wir, - und tief in uns rinnt" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 29)
  - "Nur im Dunkeln funkeln die Sterne" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 30)
  - "Wiegenlied" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 31)
  - "Schlaf, mein Kind, der Regen fällt" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 32)
  - "Und der große Herbstwind weht uns vor sich her" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 33)
  - "Es ist vorbei" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 34)
  - "Und in uns lautlos wächst der Tod" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 35)
  - "Die Städte rücken enger nachts zusammen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 36)
  - "Wenn der Nebel auf die großen Städte fällt -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 37)
  - "Ach, mit Geld läßt es sich leichter weinen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 38)
  - "Vor allen Türen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 39)
  - "Kunde" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 40)
  - "5f. Jamben" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 41)
  - "Schlaflied am Karfreitag" -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 42)
  - "Die Blätter fallen und der Regen fällt" -- working manuscript Arbeitsmanuskript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 43)
  - "Warte nur, wenn erst in Deinem Mund" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 44)
  - "Die Blätter fallen und der Regen fällt" -- working manuscript Arbeitsmanuskript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 45)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 46)
  - "Gedichtzyklus" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 47)
  - "Kleiner grüner Mond" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 48)
  - Sonett -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 49)
  - "Der Wind geht über das Stoppelfeld" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 50)
  - "Die Blätter fallen und der Regen fällt" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 51)
  - "Bruder hörst du den Regen?" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 52)
  - "Grauer Himmel - unbewegtes Meer" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 53)
  - "Argonnerwald, Argonnerwald" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 54)
  - "Alles Menschliche noch ist" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 55)
  - "Am schwersten ist es, nachts allein zu sein" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 56)
  - "Immer, wenn Wolken wandern und Züge gehen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 57)
  - "Abend" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 58)
  - "Dann" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 59)
  - Geistliche Gedichte -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 60)
  - "Warte nur, wenn erst in Deinem Mund" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 61)
  - "Der grüne Mond im grünen Glas" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 62)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 81, Folder 242, Item 63)
  - Berlin 45 -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 1)
  - "Seifenblasen" -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 2)
  - Bells of Bicetre! -- outline, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 3)
  - The club of no return -- outline, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 4)
  - Der Kranke -- working manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 5)
  - Zum Tode verurteilt -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 6)
  - Der Tod Römers -- outline, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 7)
  - The club of no return -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 8)
  - Der Kranke -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 9)
  - Berlin 45 -- notes, circa 1955 (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 10)
  - Der Kranke -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 11)
  - Berlin 45 -- notes, letter, 1964 (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 12)
  - Berlin 45 -- working manuscript, circa 1955 (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 13)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 81, Folder 243, Item 14)
  - Assorted notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 1)
  - Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites -- title designs, circa 1961 (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 2)
  - Assorted notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 3)
  - Letter draft, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 4)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- notes, circa 1929 (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 5)
  - Assorted notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 6)
  - Gam -- notes, circa 1924 (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 7)
  - La Barcarole -- notes, newspaper clipping, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 8)
  - Assorted notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 244, Item 9)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front and "Tagebuch eines Mannes, der allein lebt" -- notes, circa 1929 (Box 81, Folder 245, Item 1)
  - Kleines Schicksal -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 1-3)
  - Die Osnabrücker -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 4)
  - Gam -- notes, circa 1924 (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 5)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk -- notes, circa 1956 (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 7)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- plan, circa 1929 (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 7)
  - Leben eines Mannes unserer Zeit -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 246, Item 8-10)
  - Collection of titles, undated (Box 81, Folder 247, Item 1)
  - Practical Educational Work in Germany After the War -- working manuscript, circa 1944 (Box 81, Folder 248, Item 1-2)
  - Trinker -- notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 249, Item 1)